kara no kokoro wo terasu mono wa nani?
What brightens up an empty heart?
sakebi tsuzukeru hikari todoku made
I will keep on singing until the light reaches you
falling through the cracks kurayami e ochiteku
Falling through the cracks, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me the story of your life mada michi no tochuu
Tell me the story of your life, We're still on our way
anata o watashi wa zettai akiramenai
I will never give up on you
osaerarenai shoudou nanigenai hibi wa aijyou
Urges I can't suppress, I live for the ordinary days
natsukashii kaze ni furimukeba itsud
When I turn my cheek to a nostalgic wind
emo anata no koe ga suru yo
I always hear your voice
underdog wa wander around
Underdog will Wander around
mawari michi shitemo nigeru yori mashi yo
Even if I take the long way around,
it's better than running away
jibun de jibun o shinjirare nakucha dare wo shinjiru no?
If I can't learn to believe in myself,
then who can I believe in?
hikari ni sono te kazase
Hold up your hand to the light
shining through the clouds kurayami e ochiteku
Shining through the clouds, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me what is on your mind hateshinai yume wo
Tell me what is on your mind,
Chasing the never ending dream
oikake bokura wa zettai akiramenai
We will never give up
kotae no nai jinsei ni kujike sou ni naru kedo
Discouraged by a life without answers, but I...
don’t give it up! keep it up! turn it upside down!
Don't give it up! Keep it up! Turn it upside down!
kokoro wa tsunagatteru yo tatoe tooku hanaretemo
Our hearts will always be connected,
no matter how far apart we may be
tomo ni tomo ni ikiteyukou
Let's share this life together
The State of Affairs
FIRE
So, I told my classmates...
(ユリト)だから 同期のやつらに
言ってやったんすよ～。
that they were lucky to have
so much free time.
お前ら暇でいいなって。
It's been a month since I got here.
俺もここ来て
ひと月じゃないですか。
Isn't it about time I get to supervise
a big assignment on my own?
そろそろ でかい案件→
任されても
いい頃じゃないっすかね？
Oh, Lord Hokage!
Where was yesterday's report again?
(ユリト)ああ 火影様。
Third pile to the right,
the second one.
(カカシ)昨日の報告書って
どこだっけ？
(シカマル)３段目の右から２つ目です。
Oh, here it is.
うん。
Didn't this come with
some attachments?
ああ これね
これってたしか 添付の資料が…。
Second pile, the third one.
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
２段目の３つ目です。
お前がいてくれて助かるよ。
Oh right, Lord Hokage.
About next week's inspection...
そうだ 火影様
来週の視察の件ですけど。
I keep telling you to
just call me Kakashi.
You're way too stiff
and formal, senpai!
カカシさんでいいって
何度言えばわかんの？
肩に力 入りすぎっすよ 先輩。
And don't forget to take a break.
Efficiency gets compromised
if you don't.
それと 休憩もとってよね
能率落ちちゃうからさ。
Roger!
了解っす。
Anyway...
I didn't become a shinobi
to be chained to a desk.
ふぁ～ しっかし
デスクワークするために→
忍になったんじゃない
っつうんですよ。
How do you not get bored
doing this sort of work, senpai?
先輩
こんな退屈な仕事ばっかで→
Uh, senpai?
よく飽きないっすね。 先輩？
I haven't looked up at the clouds
in a long time.
雲を見るのも久しぶりだな。
You know, senpai,
sometimes you talk like an old man.
先輩って ときどき
オッサンみたいなこと言いますよね。
Is something bothering you?
先輩 何か
悩みごとでもあるんすか？
Huh?
No.
はあ？ ねえよ。
And, I'm done for the day!
Man!
これでよし。
We cruised through today!
や～ 今日も楽勝でしたね
んじゃ お疲れっした～。
Thanks, and see ya tomorrow!
Oh, Lord Hokage!
ああ 火影様
お疲れっした～。
See ya...
でした～。
Thanks for today.
お疲れ。
Why'd you pick a guy like that?
The adult world is complicated.
なんで あんなやつ
採ったんすか？
大人の世界では
いろいろあるんだよ。
I don't like that kind of stuff.
俺 そういうの苦手っす。
Oh?
I thought you became
one of us a while back.
あれ？ シカマルも とっくに
こっちの人間かと思ってたけど。
Give me a break!
Having more shinobi like him
just goes to show we're at peace.
勘弁してくださいよ。
でも 彼みたいな忍が増えるのも
平和になった証しかもね。
It's been two years since then.
I'm starting to get a belly...
あれから２年っすからね。
俺 最近
下腹出てきちゃった。
I don't want to hear it.
Do you keep up with training?
聞きたくないっす。
Here and there.
シカマルは 今でも鍛えてる？
You say it like that,
まあ テキト-に。
but I bet you're as
disciplined as ever.
そう言いながら どうせ
きっちりやってるんでしょ？
Why can't you just
humor me a bit?
I told him to double-check it!
かわいくないよ
そういうとこ。
あいつ
二重チェックしろつったのに。
By the way, how is it going?
Regarding that issue.
そういえば どうなってる？
例の件。
It's on the back-burner.
No contact then?
待ちっすね。
連絡なしか。
I feel bad burdening you
with it.
お前に こんな役目を押し付けて
すまないと思ってる。
I was never really
cut out to be a shinobi.
俺 もともと
忍には向いてないんすよ。
The fact that
I continue to be one...
Is to make Naruto
the Hokage one day, right?
それでも続けてるのは…。
ナルトを
いずれ火影にするため だろ？
To make sure that happens,
I can't be a child forever.
そのためには 俺もいつまでも
ガキじゃいられないんで。
Naruto's still a child, even now.
He is who he is.
ナルトは 今でもガキのまんまだ。
ヤツは ヤツです。
Oh...
How about we go grab
a bite after you're done?
なあ それ終わったら→
After this, Lord Tsuchikage
and I have a game.
久しぶりに
飯でもどうだ？
このあと 土影様と
これなんすよ。
Oh right, I saw him
at the conference yesterday.
ハハ そういえば昨日
会議で会ったな。
All he talked about was how
he would beat you this time.
今度こそ お前を負かすって
息巻いてたぞ。
Anyway, please go easy on him.
Well, half of it is work for me.
まあ お手柔らかに頼むよ。
半分
仕事みたいなもんすから。
Hey, Shikamaru...
なあ シカマル→
I wonder what it means
to become an adult?
大人になるって
どういうことなんだろうな？
(オオノキ)む～。
No, wait... This one?
うむ～ う～ん
いや違う こっちか？
How's that, young 'un?
You're speechless now, eh?
どうじゃ 小僧？
ぐうの音も出まい ワッハッハ！
Please excuse me...
Hey, don't think
I'll let you win and run!
お？
では。
ええい！
勝ち逃げなど
許すものか～！
Tsk...
I have to work twice
as hard tomorrow.
チッ… こりゃ
明日から倍だな。
HIDDEN LEAF LIBRARY
(みんな)お～！
BARBE-Q
Welcome!
Oh, there he is!
いらっしゃい！
Over here!
(チョウジ)おっ 来た来た！
(いの)こっちよ。
Sorry I'm late.
遅れてすまない。
That's the meat I was grilling!
(チョウジ)それ 僕が育てた肉！
(シカマル)ハハッ はいよ。
Here you go.
This one's done too.
Another order of kalbi please!
こっちも焼けてるわよ。
おう。
Anyway, I keep teaching this newbie
and she just doesn't get it.
カルビ追加ね！
(いの)でね その新人の子が
何度教えても直んなくてさ～。
There's one on my team too.
He reminds me of myself
and I just can't ignore him.
僕の班にも１人いるけど→
自分を見てるみたいで
放っとけないんだよね。
I wonder if
Asuma felt this way.
アスマも こんな気持だったのかなぁ。
You two have totally embraced
your roles as instructors.
２人とも もうすっかり教官だな。
Well, you're Lord Hokage's
right-hand man, aren't you?
シカマルだって 火影様の右腕でしょ。
But I don't have anyone
under me to mentor.
けど お前らみたいに→
下の面倒を見る根気
俺にはねえよ。
You're the type that prefers
to just do things yourself.
シカマルは 自分でやったほうが早い
ってタイプだもんね。
Being a loner suits me.
You two are the only ones
who are special to me.
ひとりが性に合ってるんだ。
俺にとっては
お前らだけが特別なんだよ。
I miss the old days.
なんかさ 昔が懐かしい。
Hey, we're not old enough
to be saying that.
Back then, it was normal for us
to be together 24/7.
まだ そんな歳じゃねえだろ。
だってさ
前は四六時中 一緒にいるのが→
Now, we have to set up
a time and date just to eat together.
当たり前だったでしょ。
でも今は
こうして一緒に食事するのも→
It's kinda sad, huh?
いちいち
約束しなきゃならないんだよ。
Maybe that's what it means
to become an adult.
それって なんか寂しいよね。
大人になるってのはさ
そういうことかもしれねえよな。
That's for sure.
Your temperament's changed.
確かに…
シカマル 雰囲気変わったわよね。
Huh? You've got to be kidding.
Lately, you never say,
"what a drag."
はぁ？ 勘違いだろ。
最近 めんどくせぇって
言わなくなったの 気づいてる？
Haven't you noticed?
Really?
BARBE-Q
そう… だっけ？
– Thanks for the food!
– Thank you!
(シカマル)ごちそうさん。
(いの)ごちそうさま。
They gave me gum when
I was at the register.
レジでガムくれたよ。
Doesn't this bring
back memories?
GUM
これ 懐かしくない？
I always chewed this
when I was a kid!
これ 子供の頃 よく食べたよね。
Oh, it's so sweet!
Was it always this sweet?
(いの)うわ 甘っ！
こんな甘かった？
Okay, where to next?
(チョウジ)で 次どうする？
You still wanna eat more?
Let's go BBQ hopping!
あんた まだ食べるつもり？
Sorry, I have to go.
焼肉のハシゴしようよ～。
Huh?!
悪い 俺 帰るわ。
えぇ!?
Shikamaru...
Is something on your mind?
シカマル なんか気になってること
あるんじゃない？
Your mind seems
to be wandering.
上の空っていうかさ。
It's nothing.
I have to leave the village for work,
on Allied Shinobi business.
別にねえよ。
ただの出張だって 忍連合の。
Is it the same thing Temari
and Kankuro attend?
それって
テマリとかカンクロウとかも来るやつ？
So Temari is more important
than us?
私らより
テマリのほうが大事ってか？
Oww...
What're you talking about?
イテテテテ… 何の話だよ!?
SAMURAI
And so, we hope that
it grows even more.
(長十郎)よりいっそうの
発展を願うものであります。
That concludes my activity report.
以上で活動報告を終わりますが
他に何か ご質問は？
Are there any other questions?
Regarding the long list of
missing persons after the Great War...
(黒ツチ)大戦で大量に出た
失踪者リストの件だけど→
How is the search going?
その後の捜索は どうなってるの？
It's currently under investigation.
How about the drop in shinobi requests
for three consecutive periods?
鋭意 調査中。
(オモイ)忍への依頼が ３期連続で
減少している点については？
It's currently under investigation.
You know, if it keeps dropping,
鋭意 調査中。
けどな この先も
依頼が減り続けるようなら→
it'll affect how we administer
the villages.
We should have a more
detailed report by the next meeting.
里の運営にも影響が…。
(シカマル)来月の会合には→
更に詳しい報告書を
提出できると思います。
I understand the view
忍への依頼が
減っている点について→
that a decrease in requests
for shinobi poses a concern.
危機的な見方もあることは
承知していますが→
But remember,
this is a consequence of peace.
平和に代償が伴うことも
また事実です。
If there are no more questions,
他に質問もないようですので→
we'll meet again in one month.
それでは皆さん また ひと月後に。
Hey! Wait, Shikamaru!
(テマリ)おい！ 待てよ シカマル。
ハァ…。
What's going on, Temari?
テマリ 何か用か？
You're hiding something, aren't you?
何か 隠してるんだろ？
Huh? What makes you say that?
See?
はぁ？ いきなり何だ？
ほらな。
When you answer a question
with a question,
it's proof that something's up.
質問を質問で返すときは
やましいことがある証拠だ。
What's going on in
the Hidden Leaf Village?
木ノ葉で何が起きてるんだ？
知らねえな。
I don't know what
you're talking about.
It's something you can't talk
to me about?
私にも話せないことなのか？
I said there's nothing going on!
So there's nothing I can help with?
だから何もねえよ。
私が力になれることは
ないってことか？
Nope.
I see...
ない。
そう…。
Hey, Temari...
Both you and I are representatives
of our villages...
なあ テマリ。
俺も お前も
一応は里の代表って立場なんだ。
We shouldn't pry too much
into the other's—
あんまり よそのことに
首を突っ込むのは…。
What the hell—?!
I misjudged you!
なにしやがる！
見損なったよ あんた。
So that's what made
you remember your old man.
(カカシ)ハッハッハッ！
それで
親父さんを思い出したってのか？
Yes.
He often got yelled at by
my mom for staying out all night.
えぇ 朝帰りして→
Sorry you had to go through that.
よく おふくろに
怒鳴られてたもんで。
Temari is very intuitive.
そいつは災難だったな。
She's going to find out
sooner or later
テマリは勘のいいやつです。
about the Land of Silence.
いずれはバレますよ 黙の国の件。
Many of the missing from
the Great War
and Rogue Ninja are filtering
into this mysterious land.
大戦での失踪者や抜け忍が→
大量に流れ込んでいるという
謎の国。
And there's a deep, dark rumor
that it's undertaking
shinobi missions illegally.
そして 忍の依頼を
不法に請け負っている黒い噂。
By rights, the Shinobi Alliance
should deal with this problem.
本来なら 忍連合全体で
対処すべき問題だしね。
It'll be troublesome if
they find out that
we're independently
investigating this.
うちが単独で調べていることが
連合に知れれば→
But taking action on
the Land of Silence
やっかいなことになります。
in the name of the alliance
will be touchy.
とはいえ 今 連合をあげて→
黙の国と事を構えるのも
まずいでしょ。
Just when we finally
achieved peace.
ようやく手にした
平和ですからね。
It's already been two weeks
since Sai left word
that he was infiltrating
the Land of Silence, right?
サイが黙の国に潜入すると
言い残してから もう２週間か。
We can't just stand by without
taking action any further.
このまま手をこまねいている
わけにはいきません。
It's finally here.
やっと来たか。
The state of affairs is more serious
than we previously thought.
If the Land of Silence is left
to continue as is,
(サイの声)
事態は予想以上に深刻です。
the Shinobi Alliance will
be threatened at some point.
There is one leader
at work in this land.
黙の国を野放しにすれば→
いずれは
連合の脅威となるでしょう。
His name is...
この国は たった一人の
指導者によって動かされています。
Gengo.
I've never heard that name before.
その男の名は…。
It's possible,
he will become the one
ゲンゴ。
初めて聞く名前だな。
who may very well change
the pitiful existence of shinobi...
(サイ)彼は忍という哀れな存在。
In fact, he may change
the whole framework of this world.
それどころか この世界の
枠組みそのものを変える→
I don't even know
myself anymore...
存在になるかもしれません。
This isn't good.
僕はもう 自分が
わからなくなりはじめています。
Right?
Sai led a team of ten,
comprised of the cream of
the crop among the ANBU.
まずいっすね。
だよね。
サイが率いていたのは
暗部の中でも→
It would take a formidable enemy
to wipe them out...
屈指の実力者で
構成されたチームです。
Probably...
それが全滅となると
敵も相当の手だれ。
Sai's instincts were right.
Many of the shinobi who
disappeared after the Great War
だろうね。
サイの読みは正しかった。
and Rogue Shinobi are
in the Land of Silence.
大戦の失踪者や
抜け忍たちの多くが→
I hope Sai is all right.
黙の国にいるとみて
間違いないでしょう。
He's not one to get killed
so easily, but...
サイは無事かな？
There are hints in
his message that sound
簡単に死ぬようなやつじゃ
ありません。 ですが…。
like admiration for
this man named Gengo.
文面からにじみ出る
ゲンゴという男に対する→
You don't think Sai has...?
He's very pure hearted, so...
称賛にも似た執着。
If we're to get Sai out of there
まさか サイのやつ…。
純粋だからね 彼は。
and nip the Land of Silence
in the bud...
we have just one option.
サイを救出し
黙の国の芽をつんでおく。
Could we be thinking
the same thing?
となれば
取るべき道はひとつです。
Yes.
However, you can't go.
ひょっとして
俺と同じことを考えてる？
Right...
はい。 ですが 火影様を
行かせるわけにはいきません。
To go unnoticed,
a three-man squad will be best.
だよね。
目立たず行動するには→
Could you get two good shinobi
from the ANBU?
スリーマンセルが最適です。
A three-man squad...
暗部から腕の立つのを
２名呼んでもらえますか？
You already have someone in mind
for the third member?
スリーマンセル。 もう一人は誰か
心当たりあるの？
What we're attempting is
a clear breach of faith
toward the alliance.
If worse comes to worst,
我々のやろうとしていることは
連合への背信行為です。
we would have to disavow
any knowledge of this team.
いざとなったら 切り捨てられる
人間でなければなりません。
I'll go.
You carry a big part of
the responsibilities within the alliance.
俺が行きます。
You can't...
お前にだって連合の一翼を担う
役目があるんだ。
I'm simply adding another job
to my plate.
It's useless to try to
stop you, isn't it?
それを いまさら…。
業務が１つ増えるだけです。
Still, I would have thought
you'd pick Ino and Choji.
止めても無駄か。
For this mission,
それにしても お前なら→
イノとチョウジを指名するかと
思ったけどね。
we need someone who can
control chakra and can hide us.
今回の任務に必要なのは
チャクラを操り→
And someone who has a jutsu
to make a direct hit on the target.
こちらの存在を
隠すことができるタイプと→
Besides...
実際に標的を
しとめる術を持った忍です。
Besides?
Those two have
their own lives now.
それに…。
それに？
I think I know just
the ANBU for this.
あいつらには
あいつらの生活がありますから。
They're both easy to work with...
暗部に格好の人間がいたな。
So I'm sure you'll like them.
２人とも とっても
つきあいやすい連中だから→
SHIKAMARU
What?
きっと気にいると思うよ。
Going on a business trip, senpai?
Yeah, take care of things here
for me.
あれ？ 先輩 出張っすか？
It must be nice!
I wish I could go too!
ああ あとは頼むな。
Damn it.
いいな～
俺も行きたいくらいっすよ。
Please bring me back a souvenir!
Yeah sure, I will.
はぁ～ ったく。
お土産 お願いしますよ。
This is Soku of the ANBU.
あ～ わかった わかった。
Easy to work with, huh?
(カカシ)暗部の鏃だ。
And where's the other one?
(シカマル)つきあいやすい連中ねぇ。
I am right here.
When did you—?
それで もう一人は？
(朧)ここにおります。
He's Ro.
He has the ability to freely manipulate
his own and others' chakra
いつの間に？
彼は 朧だ。
to erase all signs of his presence
or become another person.
自分や他人のチャクラの量を
自由に操って→
If I were to put it simply,
気配を完全に消したり
別人になりすます能力がある。
it's a modification of
the chakra from
わかりやすく申し上げるならば→
the point of view of
what others perceive.
I do not actually increase
the chakra of the target,
他者が知覚するという
観点においての変異にござる。
I create an anachronism
in their perception.
対象人物のチャクラを実際に
増大させられるのではなく→
Like, that's even more confusing.
知覚する側の錯誤を
生むのみにござりますな。
This one's still a kid.
Like, unthinkable, right?
(鏃)余計わかりにくいし。
In the world of shinobi,
ability is, like, everything.
こいつ まだガキじゃないですか。
心外だし。
You don't mince words.
After the Academy,
忍の世界は実力がすべてだし。
we noticed Hinoko's talents
and scouted her for the ANBU.
言うね。
ヒノコはアカデミーを出ると
すぐに才能を見込まれて→
She's only 14,
but she's already highly regarded
in the ANBU.
暗部にスカウトされた。
I asked you to like,
not to use my real name, Lord Hokage.
まだ14だが暗部内での信頼も厚い。
Your name's Hinoko?
火影様
本名で呼ぶなって言ってるし。
That's a really cute na—!
お前 ヒノコってのか。
I, like, hate to be called that name.
ずいぶん かわいらしい名前…。
I'd like you to be careful
about that.
その名前で呼ばれるのは
嫌いだし→
So, what can you do?
My weapon is a chakra needle.
そこんとこは
気をつけてもらいたいし。
で 何ができるんだ？
私の武器は チャクラの針。
Once my needle hones in
on a target,
it will not stop its pursuit until,
it like, pierces its target.
私の針は一度狙いを定めたら→
Very suitable for assassination.
標的を貫くまで
どこまでも追っていくんだし。
まさに 暗殺向きか。
I don't like,
needlessly kill.
I pierced its chakra stimulation point,
無駄な殺生はしないし。
so it's like, several times
more livelier now.
今は チャクラ活性化のツボを貫いたから
さっきより何倍も元気だし。
We'll infiltrate using Ro's jutsu,
then I'll immobilize the target
with my Shadow Strangle Jutsu,
(シカマル)朧の術で潜入し→
and Soku will finish him.
A true collaboration indeed.
The synergy in this plan is ideal.
俺の影首縛りで
標的の動きを封じ→
鏃がしとめる。
まさに相乗効果。
Like, that sounds tedious.
いわゆる シナジーが見込める
理想の組み合わせでござるな。
They're exactly what you wanted.
I have no objections...
長ったらしいし。
Then, like, what's the issue?
シカマルの要望どおりだよ。
Can you drop the "like" thing?
不満はないんすが…。
なんだし？
Like, absolutely not.
Well, it's decided.
So once everything's ready—
その しぃしぃ言うの
なんとかなんねえのか？
Would it be okay to leave
tomorrow morning?
無理だし。
決まりだな。
じゃあ 準備が整いしだい…。
It's not shogi again, is it?
出発は 明朝でもいいっすか？
I have some business
to take care of.
また 将棋とか言わないよね？
So anyway, looks like
ちょっと 用があるんすよ。
I'll be heading back a bit later,
so I won't be able to visit next month.
SHIKAKU NARA
(シカマル)んなわけで 帰るのは
少し先になりそうだから→
I have two subordinates under me.
来月は来られねえかもな。
It's not like me, huh?
この俺が
部下を２人も連れてだぜ？
柄じゃねえよな。
ASUMA SARUTOBI
Both you and my dad had someone
you'd give your lives to protect.
我が身を捧げて守るものを
親父も あんたも持ってたっけ。
But, I haven't found anyone
like that yet...
Big Brother Shika!
けど 俺には まだ…。
Mirai!
Big Brother Shika!
(ミライ)シカの兄ちゃ！
Whoa, there!
ミライ！
シカの兄ちゃ！
うわっと！
Shikamaru, you're so busy these days,
you don't need to
come every month.
(紅)シカマルも忙しい身なんだから
毎月 来てくれなくてもいいのよ。
I'm not that busy.
This is our babysitter.
そんなんじゃないですけど。
She occasionally watches
Mirai for me.
この人 ベビーシッターさん。
ときどき ミライを見てもらっててね。
Hello.
He may not look it, but he's
Lord Hokage's right-hand man.
どうも。
Please...
Oh, I see!
こう見えて 火影様の右腕なのよ。
よしてください。
I'm sorry, I still don't know
these things yet.
She just started living here.
そうなんですね。 すみません。
まだ よくわかってなくて…。
People are moving into
this village
彼女 里に移り住んだばかりなの。
all because of people like
you and the Lord Hokage.
こうして
人の往来が盛んになったのも→
Please, don't mention it.
I hope this peace will last
for a long time.
あなたや火影様のおかげね。
とんでもない。
ASUMA SARUTOBI
今の平和が
長く続くといいんだけど。
Big Brother!
Flowers!
Oh really?
You brought them for your daddy?
兄ちゃ お花！
You're so clever, Mirai!
そうか。
お父さんに持ってきたのか？
Mirai, you really love
Big Brother Shikamaru, don't you?
偉いな ミライは。
Uh-huh!
ミライは 本当に
シカマル兄ちゃんのことが大好きね。
This peace will last.
うん！
I'll make it last.
続きますよ 平和。
続けてみせます。
Why now?
Damn it!
なんで 今頃になって…。
Such bad luck.
クソ！ 縁起でもねえ…。
Hey, Shikamaru!
You're up awfully early.
(ナルト)よう！ シカマルじゃねえか。
Naruto...
ずいぶん早起きだな。
I could say
the same about you.
I got up and couldn't
go back to sleep...
ナルト…。
お前こそ 早いじゃねえか。
I'm on my way home
from Ichiraku Ramen.
なんか
朝早く 目覚めちまったから→
That shop opens that early?
一楽で ラーメン食べた帰りなんだ。
It's open 24 hours now!
こんな早くからやってんのか
あの店。
Yeah but, who eats ramen
for breakfast?
最近 24時間になったんだぜ。
I could eat it for breakfast,
lunch, and dinner.
だからって
朝っぱらから ラーメンかよ。
Half of my body's made of ramen!
朝 昼 晩 オーケーだ！
俺の体の半分は
ラーメンでできている！
Hmm?
Do I smell like garlic?
Oh...
ん？ あっ！ ニンニク臭かった？
Chew this.
GUM
そうだ。
This brings back memories!
これ 食えよ。
I love this stuff!
おぉ～！ 懐かしい…。
これ 大好きだってばよ。
See ya.
Work?
Yeah, just a little.
じゃあな。
Don't just sit around
and eat ramen.
仕事か？
あぁ ちょっとな。
Do some work.
Well, a certain someone somewhere
お前も
ラーメンばっか食ってないで 働けよ。
keeps assigning me
annoying missions...
So I won't have a break
for the next six months.
どっかの誰かさんが→
めんどくせぇ任務ばっか
持ってくっから 半年 休みなしだ。
This is the most critical time
in your life.
I know that.
お前にとって
今が いちばん大事なときなんだ。
But you know—
No buts!
わかってるってばよ！ でもよ…。
Take on as many missions
as possible,
make it so everyone says,
でも じゃねえ！
"It has to be Naruto,
no one else will do."
１つでも多くの任務をこなして→
If you think
they acknowledge you now
やっぱり ナルトでなければと
みんなに思わせるためだ。
because you're the hero
of the Great War, you're wrong.
Yeah, yeah.
大戦の英雄ってだけで
認められるほど甘くはないんだぜ。
– Hey, Naruto.
– Hmm?
You're going to become
the Hokage.
はい はい。
おい ナルト。
Don't ever forget that.
ん？
お前は火影になる男だ。
それを忘れんな。
I never go back on my word.
That's my Ninja Way.
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
それが 俺の忍道だ。
You mean "our" way.
Yeah.
俺たちの だ。
Naruto...
あぁ。
Always stay
just the way you are.
《ナルト… お前は いつまでも
今のままでいてくれ。
That's the reason why
I'm here.
そのために 俺がいるんだからな》
Anyway...
I guess it's time to go to work.
それじゃ ま…
お仕事といきますか。
kakaeta omou i tokitoshite
Sometimes, the feelings we have
kazoe kirenai itami o
Cause us immense pain
yuzurenai hokori mune ni
We've lived this entire time
imamade ikite kitadarou
With unshakeable pride in our hearts
tatakau koto de mamotte
Defending by fighting
omoigakenaku nakushite
With unexpected losses
kizutsukiai ma nande
We learn as we hurt one another
taisetsu na koto ni kizukudarou
Will we realize what's most important?
koe ga todokanai
My voice cannot reach you
soredemo (soredemo)
Even so
kokoro shinjite iyou
Let's trust our hearts
zenshin zenrei kimi wo mamoru yo
I will protect you with every essence of my being
towa ni sou towa ni
For all eternity
nankaidatte tachiagare yo
Stand up again and again
sono ishi de (sono ishi de)
By your own volition
ungai souten asu wo egaku yo
Don't give in; create a new day
tomo ni sou tomo ni
Together with friends
itsudatte akirameru
Never ever give up
na michi wo hirakou
Let's open up the path
ruru
On and on
I humbly guarantee that
we will be able to deceive
the enemy's eyes with this.
Like, if we kill all of the lookouts,
it will be easy to pass
through the checkpoint.
It would spell trouble
if we do that
and they found out
the Leaf's involved.
Don't underestimate the enemy.
If we linger too long,
we'll only like, up the chances
of the enemy noticing us.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Shikamaru's Story,
A Cloud Drifting in the Silent Dark,
Part 2: Dark Clouds"
Soku, trust me.